A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, A-E FA391
Rockefeller Archive Center
- DeVinney, Leland C.
  - 1956 January 4-June 28, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 169 pages (Box 117, Reel M Dev 2, Frame 115)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. DeVinney documents a trip to Puerto Rico to discuss the administration of agricultural agencies to more effectively deliver services and analyze current agricultural production procedures. A trip to Washington D. C. and Chicago is taken to explore research options about a study of prisoners readjusting to society and the reduction of recidivism. Includes a note entitled "Sources of Information About Research in Criminology"
    Social sciences; United States; Prisoners; Puerto Rico; International relations; Political science; Economics; Agriculture; Diaries
  - 1956 July 2-December 28, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 143 pages (Box 117, Reel M Dev 2, Frame 284)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The diary also documents DeVinney's travels to Berkley, Chicago and Wisconsin. These trips are to gather information such as urbanization, agriculture and university education for research to increase India's academic prestige for a future trip and a RF social science program in India.
    International relations; Prisoners; Agriculture; Diaries; United States; Puerto Rico
  - 1957 January 3-April 30, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 263 pages (Reel M Dev 2, Frame 429, Box 117)
    Diaries; Urbanization; United States; Social sciences; International relations; Economics; Agriculture
  - 1957 May 1-December 30, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 225 pages (Reel M Dev 2, Frame 692, Box 118)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The RF is interested in proposals that advance sociology as a scientific discipline. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects, andfinancing current and future research. The diary documents DeViney's travels to Philadelphia, Washington D.C., Skytop, Pennsylvania and Chicago. The visit to Washington D.C. was to attend the meeting of the American Sociological Society. The visit to Skytop, Pennsylania was to attend the Social Science Resaerch Council (SSRC) board of directors meeting.
    Urbanization; United States; Social sciences; Population; International relations; Diaries; Economics
  - 1958 January 3-March 29, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 219 pages (Reel M Dev 2, Frame 918, Box 118)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The bulk of the diary focuses on a trip to India to assess current academic programs, RF help requests, research and cultural activities. The cities that were visited include Bombay, Poona, Ceylon, Madras, Andhra, Rangoon, Calcutta, Dacca, Agra, Delhi, Lucknow and Karachi.
    Agriculture; Economics; Burma; Bangladesh; Pakistan; International relations; India; England; Urbanization; United States; Social sciences; Population; Diaries
  - 1958 April 2-December 27, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 231 pages (Reel M Dev 3, Frame 1, Box 118)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. During this period DeVinney makes trips to Ann Arbor and Chicago.
    Social sciences; United States; Diaries
  - 1959 January 2-May 28, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 182 pages (Reel M Dev 3, Frame 233, Box 118)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research.
    Diaries; Social sciences; United States
  - 1959 June 1-December 29, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 144 pages (Box 119, Reel M Dev 3, Frame 417)
    Diaries; United States; Social sciences
  - 1960 January 1-February 10, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 198 pages (Box 119, Reel M Dev 3, Frame 563)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The bulk of the diary focuses on a trip to India to assess current academic programs, RF help requests, research and cultural activities. The cities that were visited include Rangoon, Calcutta, Dacca, Madras, Trivandrum, Bombay, Ahedabad, Delhi, Agra, Lahore, Karachi and London.
    Diaries; Agriculture; Burma; India; International relations -- United States -- 1950-1960.; Economics; Education; Social sciences; Statistics; Pakistan; Population; United States; Urbanization
  - 1960 February 16-July 5, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 196 pages (Reel M Dev 3, Frame 760, Box 119)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. DeVinney returns to the New York office after the trip to South Asia. In addition to his interviews, he attends several conferences, seminars and meetings including "Annual Meeting of the Population Association of America" in Washington D.C., conference on "Preference Analysis and Subjective Measurements" in Princeton, New Jersey, the "American Law Institute" meetings, Council for Cultural and Economic Affairs, The Asia Society's "Democracy in Asia Series" and a seminar on the urbanization in India in Berkeley, California.
    Urbanization; Social sciences; United States; Diaries; Law; Population; Economics; International relations
  - 1960 July 6-December 29, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 193 pages (Reel M Dev 3, Frame 956, Box 119)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Conferences on "National Economic Policies and the Common Market", "Inflation and Growth in Latin America" and Research in Family Planning" are attended at the Rockefeller Foundation Bellagio Center ("Villa Serbelloni") in Bellagio, Italy. The month of December details a trip to the Southern United States.
    Diaries; African Americans; Family planning; International relations; Economics; Social sciences; Race relations; Population; Italy; Urbanization; United States
  - Trip to U.S. South, December 1960; DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 61 pages (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 1, Box 119)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. This month details a trip to the Southern United States. Visits include Norfolk, Virginia; Chapel Hill, Raleigh, Durham, Charlotte and Greensboro North Carolina as well as Atlanta, Georgia, Gainesville and Tallahassee, Florida. Topics discussed on this trip include desegregation and the civil rights movement as DeVinney visits various colleges and newspapers in the southern regional council.
    Southern States; Social sciences; Race relations; Urbanization; United States; Diaries; Civil rights movement; African Americans
  - 1961 January 4-April 1, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 144 pages (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 62, Box 120)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and DeVinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. A trip to Chicago, Illinois is taken to check on the progress of the Population Research and Training Center of the University of Chicago. A trip to India is taken. Only the travels to Bombay and the trip index are included with this diary. In Bombay, DeVinney checks out the progress of the Demographic Training and Research Center which is slow, understaffed and without UN representation on its Advisory Committee. The Department of Economics of the University of Bombay is visited and summaries of different studies are outlined as well.
    This diary includes an Index to DeVinney's Asia Trip (March 30-April 29) and the diary entries for the first few days of the trip.
    Agriculture; Economics; International relations; Italy; Population; Race relations; Diaries; Social sciences; United States; Urbanization
  - Asia Trip Index, 1961 March-April; DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation (Box 120, Reel M Dev 4, Frame 182)
  - 1961 April 3-29, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 172 pages (Box 120, Reel M Dev 4, Frame 220)
    File continues diary record of DeVinney's Asian trip. DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The diary focuses on a trip to Asia to assess current academic programs, RF help requests, research and cultural activities. Summaries of current studies are included as well. The cities that were visited include Poona, New Delhi, Calcutta, Dacca, Madras, Madras, Djakarta, Djokjakarta, Bogor, and Manila.
    Diaries; Agriculture; Economics; India; Indonesia; International relations; Pakistan; Population; Philippines; United States; Social sciences; Urbanization
  - 1961 May 3-July 28, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 114 pages (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 393, Box 120)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Notes on the annual meeting of the "Population Association of America" are included as well.
    United States; Diaries; Social sciences; Population
  - 1961 September 5-December 29, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C. (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 512, Box 120)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Notes on the International Population Conference are included as well.
    Social sciences; Population; Diaries; United States
  - 1962 January 4-31, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 152 pages (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 653, Box 120)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The diary focuses on a trip to Asia to assess current academic programs, RF help requests, research and cultural activities. Summaries of current studies are included as well. The institutions that were visited include Gokhale Institute of Politics and Economics, Institute of Economic Growth, University of Delhi, Punjab University, Indian Statistical Institute, University of Dacca, Chulalongkorn University, Thammaset University and Kasetsart University.
    Diaries; Indonesia; International relations; Economics; Education; Political science; United States; Population; Pakistan; Social sciences; Philippines; Thailand; Agriculture
  - Asia Trip, January 11-February 15, 1962 (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 657, Box 120)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The beginning of the diary continues Devinney's trip to Asia. It documents the progress and development of many foreign educational institutions including University of Malaya, University of Singapore, University of the Philippines, University of Hong Kong and University of Tokyo. He returns to the RF office and continues to meet and interview professionals.
  - 1962 February 3-May 29, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 148 pages (Box 120, Reel M Dev 4, Frame 806)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. Interviews describes the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The beginning of the diary continues Devinney's trip to Asia. It documents the progress and development of many foreign educational institutions including University of Malaya, University of Singapore, University of the Philippines, University of Hong Kong and University of Tokyo. He returns to the RF office and continues to meet and interview professionals.
    United States; Malaysia; Philippines; Political science; Social sciences; Education; Economics; Diaries; Japan; International relations; China
  - 1962 June 1-October 31, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 144 pages (Reel M Dev 4, Frame 954, Box 121)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. Interviews describes the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. A trip to the University of Chicago is taken and extended conversations regarding the general program of fellowships and grants in aid services of the Social Science Research Council are held.
    Diaries; Economics; Population; Social sciences; United States; Urbanization
  - 1962 November 1-December 31, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 145 pages (Box 121, Reel M Dev 5, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The documented interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The diary documents Devinney's trip to Latin America. It documents the progress and development of many foreign educational institutions, and the Rockefeller Foundation Agricultural Program. He returns to the RF office and continues to meet and interview professionals.
    United States; Social sciences; Peru; Family planning; Economics; Argentina; Brazil; Colombia; Chile; Diaries; Agriculture
  - 1963 January 2-August 29, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 194 pages (Box 121, Reel M Dev 5, Frame 146)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The documented interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research.
    Population; Diaries; United States; Social sciences
  - 1963 September 4-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 221 pages (Reel M Dev 5, Frame 340, Box 121)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The documented interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. DeVinney attends a few conferences including Conference of the Population on the Current and Potential Roles of Foundation and AID with respect to population problems in Latin America, the American Council on Education's Conference on expanding Opportunities for Negroes in Higher Education, and Conference on Race Relations Research. A trip to the Southern United States is taken as well.
    Diaries; Social sciences; Race relations; Population; Education; Black studies
  - 1964 January 2-April 30, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 265 pages (Box 121, Reel M Dev 5, Frame 566)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The documented interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. DeVinney attended Educational Services Incorporated meeting at MIT of historically black college presidents and others for discussion on higher education. He also attended Mayor Wagner of New York City's meeting of national organization representatives to hear discussions of the Governments War on Poverty.
    United States; Diaries; Poverty -- Economic conditions; Social sciences; Education; Population; Black studies
  - 1964 May 1-September 30, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 216 pages (Box 121, Reel M Dev 5, Frame 836)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The documented interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. DeVinney attended multiple conferences including Convocation on Equal Justice Under Law, Informal Conference of the Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation Teaching Interns, Research Conference on Education and Cultural Deprivation, and the annual meeting of the Population Association of America. He also visits the University of Wisconsin and assesses their departmental programs, research studies and cultural activities.
    Black studies; United States; Diaries; Population; Social sciences; Economics
  - 1964 October 1-December 30, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 194 pages (Reel M Dev 6, Frame 1, Box 122)